- this whole competition it's the first
of the new series of the diving World
Series residue so here can handle Ella
or Megan really upset them Tonya couch
is capable of some high-quality diving
but it's the 16 year old
Alejandro a Rothko who'll get us
underway she participated in the 2012
Olympics in the synchronised 10-meter
platform now she's going solo and she'll
start us off the order of divers Orosco
couch filly on panda Layla's been Tito
and Lu Li Jie is the judges seven judges
the best two scores and the worst two
scores will be taken out of the
reckoning the three in the middle
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
will determine the score for each
particular dive in the women's event
there are 5 dives each has been
predetermined degree of difficulty is
known in advance coaches getting ready
mandela's coach
so the Guadalajara born Orosco for
Mexico will get us underway women's 10
metre platform seventh of eight events
at this diving World Series event in
Beijing athletes then have to think of
her in the passport stamped and moving
on to the United Arab Emirates because
Dubai is next week firstly focus on this
[Applause]
this will be a forward three and a half
somersault in the pike position degree
of difficulty three
nicely delivered
[Music]
getting the first dive out of the way so
important you're looking for those 70s
mid-70s if you are down there having
first to get yourself up and running
and then let's go that's nicely executed
toes were together which is always a
good indication solid score solid start
of 67.5 for Orosco
this is 24 year old Tonya couch hails
from Plymouth in the southwest of
England having from Great Britain
it's a backward two and a half
somersault with one and a half twists
nice clean entry from Tanya a three
point two degree of difficulty to get
her five dives up and running again
anything round mid-70s is a solid start
turn these neighbors will be looking for
the mid-80s but I think mid seventies
it's he's just about right toes nicely
pointed entry good the seventy five
point two score two eights and a seven
point five the judges scores the count
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
first of the two Canadians this is
Rosalyn filly on tiny
driver bundle of energy forward three
and a half somersault
nice confidence approach and the coaches
are happy they think she's nailed it
when a bronze at the 2012 Summer
Olympics in the synchro event
spotting the entry she's picked up 63
points which is possibly a little bit
less than I think the coaches reckon she
deserved three sevens the scores the
count and the instant feedback from all
the coaches right Malaysia's panda Laila
ringing bronze medalist at the 2012
Olympics in this competition forward
three and a half somersaults in the pike
position the agree of difficulty 3.0
[Applause]
can a lovely clean entry into the water
from handle Ella still only 21 years of
age comes from East Malaysia Sarawak
there's much of a training up here in
Beijing
she's picked up a 76.5 opening-round
skull
that's a very solid start from handle
Allah making been fatal
she use up next the first of her five
dives will be a forward three-and-a-half
somersault 107 B as they call it the
same as we've just seen from panda Leila
[Applause]
twenty-five-year-old who hails from
Montreal in Canada again there's good
reaction from her coaches she went had
qualifying group earlier on this morning
which is always good for confidence nice
tight Pike spots the entry
toes nice and close together seventy
three point five and eight point five
and two eights scores the counting eight
the lowest any of these seven judges
awarded up now then the favorite woohoo
yeah
[Music]
the dive of choice the forward three and
a half somersault in pike
[Applause]
rapturous applause
she's rather overshadowed by chain rule
in is Lucretia one of these tournaments
in last year's World Series event
she's got off to a cracking start here
nice tight Pike Conference approach
straight legs out early into the dive
and a perfect entry 82.5 is the
unofficial scoring card the official
confirmation comes now indeed eighty two
point five and nine point five and two
nines anything nine point five is
perceived to be excellent and that's a
first round lead as expected for
Lucretia and the LaLaurie wrong from
Malaysia currently in second place one
point three points ahead of Britain's
Tonya couch with Megan bonafide to a
further one point seven now in fourth
place good start
back to Alejandra Orosco
she'll start this time with an arm stand
and then we'll release into a back
double somersault we have difficulty
three point two
looking for the approach you're looking
for how solid the armstand is
[Applause]
athletic agility front strength required
at the top of the dive and then you've
got to execute and I think she's
executed a pretty solid dive
[Music]
toes nicely together at the finale
that's always a good indication and a 75
point two for a total of 142 point seven
is good effort by the girl from
Guadalajara on your couch from Great
Britain in would three and a half
somersault three point two degree of
difficulty
[Music]
lovely strong stance on tiptoes
and a good execution it's got a a
gymnastic background has Tonya
[Music]
quickly into the pike perhaps didn't
just spot her entry into the water
perfectly it's solid though seventeen
point four to seven point five and a
seven counting overall 145 point six
coaches are poolside instant feedback
from just about every dive filly on
backwards three-and-a-half somersault
degree of difficulty her higher so far
three point three
[Applause]
twenty-six-year-old native of Quebec
[Music]
so they've been rushed that she's just
trying to get out of the back somersault
makes them comfortably toes pointed
sixty nine point three
for stretches the
coaching tip as panda lella prepares
backwards two and a half somersaults in
the bike position currently second after
the first round
that's very nicely delivered
[Music]
good aggressive movements into the bike
it's early arts back just a little bit
over
[Music]
to giving her a bigger splash than they
probably deserved it's a sixty nine
point six eighths across the board on
forty six point one so she'll be at the
very least in the top three
what depends on the dive executed
when I can penetrate Oh
she took a long time to settle in with
three and a half somersaults in the tuck
position
she needs seventy two point six to leap
rope and Ella she really did take a long
time to set herself before getting into
that tuck
[Music]
and the entry
exactly perpendicular so Megan a 64 for
137.5
[Music]
dangerous you might drop from second to
fifth such as the tightness of
competition in this woman's final this
the clear leader from the first round an
inward three and a half somersault in
Tuck
just that little bit of extra height
tight somersaults
[Music]
nice tighter calm he seems to have so
much time I'm barely a ripple on entry
into the pool
it's a 70 a 2.4 or Lucia
top ranked again an 8.5 was a nine
marked by one of the judges as the
highest and the 7.5 chopped off so after
two rounds we see our leads 14.8 points
leer upon della ringing who is just
point five clear of Tonya couch that's a
good battle anyone of second to six
could be in the podium at the end of
five rounds but good star from pandal
Ella Tonya very competitive but
outstanding from the Chinese athlete new
apprecia
we are at the Water Cube the venue for
the diving World Series 2014 the first
competition of the season here in
Beijing it's the eighth season of the
FINA diving world series sponsored this
year by NBC lighting Mexican fans
everywhere
Alejandro Roscoe great experience for
the 16 year old
[Applause]
a three point two degree of difficulty
for that in word three-and-a-half
somersault the youngest-ever athlete to
represent Mexico at the 2012 Olympics
[Music]
it's a very solid dive recognized by the
judges little peek at the scoreboard
seventy-two 37.5 the scores the count
from the judges little knot of approval
from her coaches on the poolside Tonya
couch forward three and a half
somersault
good confidence approach nice spring
into the dive just gets out a little bit
of extra air
what's the execution like in the
the marking is a 67.5 didn't bring nods
of approval from sonia i think she
thought it was a little bit better than
that goes to the coaches fillion
currently ranked six but a good dive
here can really elevator
this will be an inward two and a half
somersault from pike
[Applause]
spotted that very nicely it's a 2.8
degree of difficulty so the execution
has got to be just about perfect to pick
up good points anything approaching
Lehigh 60s 70s is a job very well done
she won't be far off that
as type I can release toes pointed
shoots the entry
2/8 in a 7.5 and stretch 198 point 10 is
the total of a sixty five point eight
score by the judges handle Ella from the
arm stand this would be a back double
somersault they have to go through each
of the disciplines throughout their five
done five dives it'll push off on the
arms absolutely essential
it's a good strong arm stand
I think she scored highly on that one
twist is strong the toes are pointed
them perfectly together it's always the
last little clue that's the important
element the little push just as you're
falling nice clean entry handle Ella
he's rewarded with a seventy six point
eight
it's approaching their the very good
category when fato was a genuine
contender after the first two rounds
have slipped away a little bit a three
point three degree of difficulty
wasn't the perfect entry
now back with three and a half
somersault in the Tuck did you get out
of the tuck in time it's plenty of
spring into the Tuck but coming out of
it she's it's a big splash there the
entries such an important element
just unable to flick the legs for 10
meters is a long way up as soon as
you're in the air
it disappears very quickly 57.8 lay
leader you piece yeah this is the arm
stand you followed by a backwards double
somersault
lovely great form and great strength on
the arm stand perfectly perpendicular
then the little push away together day
time to perform this somersault elements
in the execution and an excellent clean
entry
high marks almost guaranteed for that
again that's the element and she just
buys herself extra time almost too much
extra time
you PC up three nines countin 86.4 best
dive of the competition it's the best
dive of the competition so far
18 dive so far 12 still to go to each
for each of the competitors still handle
eller holding on to second place in
factually strengthen happen Orosco the
young Mexican leapfrog Tonya couch into
the podium positions
[Music]
as you can see healthy attendance for
this diving competition
we do head off around the globe
[Music]
and the big screens
and what they curse and she knows she's
got fans in the audience does alejandro
now she just needs to focus
literally fourth round the grave
difficulty selected three point to the
time is a backwards two and a half
somersaults with one and a half twists
currently ranked third solid dive to
keep on the podium
[Applause]
now they can be pretty proud of that
effort token Orosco she's put in a very
consistent series of dives which for
youngsters is very often one of the
difficulties of getting consistency
grants one two and three were sixty
seven point five seventy five seventy
two and this has added another seventy
two consistent delivery consistently
impressing the judges
you couch by contrast started well and
has faded just a little bit a 3.2 degree
of difficulty its Tania's time with the
arm stand with her gymnastic background
this should be a cinch
[Applause]
[Music]
good arm strength to push off
that's where the extra strength comes in
to buy you the time to approach and the
toes together 70 to solid seven point
five seven point five seven point five
[Music]
fully understand with the Armstrong arms
done
[Music]
different technique on the on stand and
a push came from much higher she wasn't
pushing away off the board she was
pushing up off the board tightly into
the pike
[Music]
in quest as ever sixty nine point three
the score for a to sixty-seven handle
Ella she's had a good series of dives so
far she's got an inward three and a half
somersault three point two degree of
difficulty currently second needs to
keep the focus so any one year old from
Sarawak on East Malaysia
a three point two degree of difficulty
in with three and a half somersaults
with tuck
[Music]
toes were together but
see tighter tuckfrump and illallah the
cleanest entries at this level of
competition the slightest error is
really exaggerated sixty eight point
eight for the score for panda Leila will
not be good enough to keep her in second
place it is for the moment
[Music]
bendito
don't start with a triple somersault the
big splash at the end is a bit of a
giveaway
it's not a bad dive it's just that the
execution and the entry will be
penalized hybrids all interns
athleticism but just gone over the top a
little bit on the entry that will cost
her points from the judges while the
harshest of critics yep three sixes of
the scores that count fifty nine point
four a three point three degree
difficulty for the current leader
Lucretia
she there nothing to suggest that she
won't be in the Boxee come round five
a three point three degree of difficulty
and she's quickly into the Tuck again
it's the time of the Chinese athletes
when they come out of the somersaults
seventy nine point two
I her standards an ordinary dive but my
international standards topped your top
drawer
she still leads the waiters you Keisha
Antonella still holds on in fact added
to lead in second place
Orosco holds on to third and Sonia couch
it's got some work to do one point six
points to make up on this final round of
dives
just comparing like with like that
[Music]
shot on the left have the the leader PCR
how tight cheese into the tuck how
smooth she was out into the final entry
fifth round the backward three and a
half somersault for Alejandra Orosco
this is her toughest dive for the
competition currently in third what a
result this would be if she can maintain
it
Oh entry into the water is poor she'll
be one marked down for that she
certainly had the elevation at the
approach
she's being marked right down just
couldn't get out of the somersaults and
that's a disappointing end it's just a
34.7
put it down to experience that's what
top competitions all about you've got no
margin for error
Tonya couch she's got a chance now a
podium places hers for the taking
nicely delivered at the reverse two and
a half somersault with tuck and it was a
graceful effort the degree of difficulty
is only 2.8 that means the execution has
got to be well-nigh perfect and it's a
solid total low to mid-70s will suffice
it's so much time and a very graceful
effort from the 24 year old from
Plymouth
a nine and 28.5 counts seventy two point
eight that's an excellent conclusion a
probable podium place for Tonya couch
two and a half somersaults with one and
a half twists a degree of difficulty
abut 3.24 Rozlyn filial
really nicely executed
attacks the first elements yet the
twists I've been operational and the
dive is halfway done
it just takes off seventy five point two
at best I buy some margin for Roslin
feel young now pandal alluring on a
backward two-and-a-half somersaults one
half twists as we've just seen degree of
difficulty three point two currently
second very consistent performer panda
LaLaurie wrong
beautiful entry all those hours in the
gym in the pool working hard
strategizing perfecting it makes it
worthwhile when you're producing
performances which is a definite podium
probably second for pandal Ella that's
an excellent performance from pandal
Ellering on
confidence straight legs toes together
clean as a whistle
[Music]
seventy six point eight it deserves the
smile three sixty eight point five she
knows she's thrilled to bits same died
for Megan been fatal the Canadian
again really nicely executed arguably
the best dive of the tournament and I
think statistically he will see it's the
best eye of the tournament almost
inseparable from what we just saw from
handle Ellery Nong who was watching
lyrical about that
they Quebec native has done well there
moves into fourth place Roscoe's
disastrous final round will drop her to
the bottom of the pile that's better
says the coach so this to crown a queen
you wish yeah
[Applause]
very satisfying
sound as she enters the water barely a
ripple
[Music]
and as the scores are read out it equals
the best performance of this particular
competition in 86.4 from Lucretia the
outstanding diver
the Chinese has is so often the case for
setting the standards for the others to
follow
[Music]
she's just climbing out of the shadows
of general in
confirmation bronze for Tonya couch for
on Great Britain panda lettering on from
Malaysia picks up the silver you PC are
picking up as expected the gold the
Canadians fourth and fifth their
teenager orosco she had a good
competition up until the final dive
which you've got to execute and I think
she's executed a pretty solid dive
toes nicely together the finale that's
always a good indication and a 75.2 for
a total of 142 point seven is good
effort by the girl from Guadalajara on
your couch from Great Britain in would
three and a half somersault three point
two degree of difficulty
[Music]
lovely strong stance on tiptoes
and a good execution it's got a a
gymnastic background has Tonya
[Music]
quickly into the bag perhaps didn't just
spot her entry into the water perfectly
it's solid though seventeen point four
to seven point five to seven counting
overall 145 point six
coaches are poolside instant feedback
from just about every dive filly on
backwards three and a half somersault
degree of difficulty her higher so far
three point three
[Applause]
twenty-six-year-old native of Quebec
[Music]
so they've been rushed and she's just
trying to get out of the back somersault
it makes them comfortably toes pointed
sixty nine point three
for stretches the coaching tip as pandal
Ella prepares backwards two and a half
somersaults in the bike position
currently second after the first round
that's very nicely delivered
[Music]
good aggressive movements into the bike
surely odds back just a little bit over
[Music]
giving a bigger splash than they
probably deserved it's a sixty nine
point six eighths across the board on
forty six point one so she'll be at the
very least in the top three what depends
on the dive executed
when I can penetrate Oh
took a long time to settle in with three
and a half somersaults in the tuck
position
she needs seventy two point six to leap
rope and Ella
she really really elevator
this will be an inward two-and-a-half
somersault from pike
[Applause]
spotted that very nicely it's a 2.8
degree of difficulty so the execution
has got to be just about perfect to pick
up good points anything approaching
Lehigh 60s 70s is a job very well done
she won't be far off that
nice type I can release toes pointed
shoots the entry
2/8 in a 7.5 then stretch 198 point 10
is the total of a sixty five point eight
score by the judges angle Ella from the
arm stand this would be a back double
somersault they have to go through each
of the disciplines throughout their five
done five dives
little push-off on the arms absolutely
essential it's a good strong arm stand
I think she's scored highly on that one
twist is strong the toes are pointed
them perfectly together it's always the
last little clue that's the important
element the little push just as you're
falling nice clean entry bundle Ella is
rewarded with a seventy six point eight
it's approaching their the very good
category
when fato was a genuine contender after
the first two rounds have slipped away a
little bit a 3.3 degree of difficulty
wasn't the perfect entry
now back with three and a half
somersault in the Tuck did you get out
of the tuck in time it's plenty of
spring into the Tuck but coming out of
it she's it's a big splash there the
entries such an important element
just unable to flick the legs for 10
meters is a long way up as soon as
you're in the air it disappears very
quickly 57.8 play leader you Chris yeah
this is the arm stand you followed by a
backwards double somersault
lovely great form and great strength on
the arm stand perfectly perpendicular a
little push away together day time to
perform this somersault elements in the
execution and an excellent clean entry
high marks almost guaranteed for that
again that's the element and she just
buys herself extra time almost too much
extra time
you PC up three 9s countin 86.4 best
dive of the competition it's the best
dive of the competition so far
18 dive so far 12 still to go to each
for each of the competitors still handle
eller holding on to second place in
factually strengthen Anton Orosco the
young Mexican leapfrog Tonya couch into
the podium positions
[Music]
- this whole competition this the first
of the new series of the diving World
Series residue so here Camp Randall Ella
or Megan really upset them Tonya couch
is capable of some high-quality diving
but it's the 16 year old
Alejandro Rothko who'll get us underway
she participated in the 2012 Olympics in
the synchronised 10-meter platform now
she's going solo and she'll start us off
the order of divers Orosco couch filly
on Panda Layla's been Tito and Lu Li Jie
is the judges seven judges the best two
scores and the worst two scores will be
taken out of the reckoning the three in
the middle multiplied by the degree of
difficulty will determine the score for
each particular dive in the women's
event there are five dives each is being
predetermined the degree of difficulty
is known in advance coaches getting
ready and ellas coach
so the Guadalajara born Orosco for
Mexico will get us underway women's 10
metre platform seventh of eight events
at this diving World Series event in
Beijing athletes then have to think of
her in the passport stamped and moving
on to the United Arab Emirates because
Dubai is next week firstly focus on this
[Applause]
this will be a forward three-and-a-half
somersault in the pike position degree
of difficulty 3 getting the first dive
out of the way so important you're
looking for those 70s mid 70s if you are
down there having first to get yourself
up and running
and the Roscoe that's nicely executed
toes were together which is always a
good indication solid score solid start
of 67.5 for Orosco
this is 24 year old Tonya couch hails
from Plymouth in the southwest of
England having from Great Britain
it's a backward two and a half
somersault with one and a half twists
nice clean entry from Tanya a three
point two degree of difficulty to get
her five dives up and running
[Music]
again anything round mid 70s as a solid
start
Chinese neighbors will be looking for
the mid 80s but I think mid seventies
its he's just about right toes nicely
pointed entry good the seventy five
point two score two eights and a seven
point five the judges scores the count
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
first of the two Canadians this is
Rosalie and filly on tiny divert bundle
of energy forward three-and-a-half
somersault
nice confidence approach and the coaches
are happy they think she's nailed it
when a bronze at the 2012 Summer
Olympics in the synchro event
spotting the entry she's picked up at 63
points he did take a long time to set
herself before getting into that tuck
[Music]
and the entry
not exactly perpendicular so Megan a 64
for 137.5
[Music]
dangerous you might drop from second to
fifth such as the tightness of
competition in this woman's final this
the clear leader from the first round an
inward three and a half somersault in
Tuck
just that little bit of extra height
tight somersaults
[Music]
nice tighter call he seems to have so
much time I'm barely a ripple on entry
into the pool
it's a 78 2.4 or Lucy up
top ranked again an 8.5 was a nine
marked by one of the judges as the
highest and the 7.5 chopped off after
two rounds we see our leads 14.8 points
leer upon della ringing who is just
point five clear of Tonya couch that's a
good battle anyone of second to six
could be in the podium at the end of
five rounds but good star from pandal
Ella Tonya very competitive but
outstanding from the Chinese athlete new
apprecia
we are at the Water Cube the venue for
the diving World Series 2014 the first
competition of the season here in
Beijing it's the eighth season of the
FINA diving world series sponsored this
year by NBC lighting Mexican fans
everywhere
Alejandro Roscoe great experience for
the 16 year old
[Applause]
a three point two degree of difficulty
for that in word three-and-a-half
somersault the youngest-ever athlete to
represent Mexico at the 2012 Olympics
[Music]
it's a very solid dive recognized by the
judges little peek at the scoreboard
seventy-two 37.5 the scores the count
from the judges little knot of approval
from her coaches on the poolside Tonya
couch forward three and a half
somersault
good confidence approach nice spring
into the dive just gets out a little bit
of extra air
what's the execution like in the
the marking is a 67.5 didn't bring knobs
of approval from Sonia thinks she
thought it was a little bit better and
that goes to the coaches
Fillion currently ranked six but a good
dive here which is possibly a little bit
less than I think the coaches reckoned
she deserved three sevens the scores the
count and instant feedback from all the
coaches all right Malaysia's Panda
Lehren Hong bronze medalist at the 2012
Olympics in this competition forward
three and a half somersaults in the pike
position the agree of difficulty 3.0
[Applause]
can a lovely clean entry into the water
from handle Ella still only 21 years of
age comes from East Malaysia Sarawak
there's much of a training up here in
Beijing
she's picked up a 76.5 opening-round
skull
that's a very solid start from handle
Allah making been fatal
she use up next the first of her five
dives will be a forward three-and-a-half
somersault 107 B as they call it the
same as we've just seen from panda Leila
[Applause]
twenty-five-year-old who hails from
Montreal in Canada again there's good
reaction from her coaches she went had
qualifying group earlier on this morning
which is always good for confidence nice
tight Pike spots the entry
toes nice and close together seventy
three point five and eight point five
and two eights scores the counting eight
the lowest any of these seven judges
awarded up now then the favorite woohoo
yeah
[Music]
the dive of choice the forward three and
a half somersault in pike
[Applause]
rapturous applause
this is another overshadow by chain rule
in is Lucretia one of these tournaments
in last year's World Series event
she's got off to a cracking start here
nice and tight Pike Conference approach
straight legs out early into the dive
and a perfect entry 82.5 is the
unofficial scoring card the official
confirmation comes now indeed eighty-two
point five and nine point five and two
nines anything nine point five is
perceived to be excellent and that's a
first round lead as expected for you
Keisha Antonella Rin Hong from Malaysia
currently in second place one point
three points ahead of Britain's Tonya
couch with Megan bonafide to a further
one point seven now in fourth place good
start
back to Alejandra Orosco
she'll start this time with an arm stand
we release into a a back double
somersault we have difficulty 3.2
you're looking for the approach you're
looking for how solid the armstand is
[Applause]
athletic agility front strength required
at the top of the dive and they